Guide to the General Collection Manuscript Music Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893
  - Music
    - Sapho
      - Fragments from Sapho, [circa 1851?]; 2 ms. score fragments ([15] p.); 37 cm. and smaller. (Box Oversize Folder 54)
        Fragments, holograph, from Sapho's aria, "O Cythèrée," full score, and a duet, act 3, for Sapho and Phaon, vocal score.
        Purchased from Musikantiquariat Hans Schneider on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Unidentified
      - "Andante", undated; [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 49)
        Music for piano, 4 hands, holograph.
        Title from caption of prima part.
        Parts are on facing pages.
        Purchased from Lisa Cox on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1998.
      - "Cantatrici villane: opera buffa in due atti: sestetto, nell' atto 1 / Ch. Gounod", 1841; 1 ms. score ([19] p.); 23 x 28 cm. (Box Folder 384)
        Score, holograph, dated at Rome.
        Purchased from Jean-Jacques Faure on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1998.
      - "Choral et fugue: en mi mineur: pour le piano / par Ch. Gounod", [18--]; 1 ms. music fragment ([2] p.); 35 cm., bound in volume, 36 cm. (Box Volume 38)
        Holograph fragment, with printer's markings. Bound by a former owner with a complete copyist's manuscript, with annotations by Gounod.
        Title from cover of fragment.
        Holograph dedication to Antoine Marmontel.
        Publisher's number: A C 9801 (manuscript printer's annotation).
        Purchased from Lisa Cox on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
      - "Je suis honteux", undated; [1] p. of ms. music; 37 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 51)
        Sketch for an unidentified vocal work, with incomplete bass accompaniment, holograph.
        Title from first line.
        Possibly for an opera titled Deux roses.
        Purchased from Les Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1999.
      - "La Piémontaise / paroles de A. Barbier; musique de Ch. Gounod", [1859?]; 1 ms. score ([11] p.); 18 x 27 cm. (Box Folder 383)
        Music for chorus (TTBB), composed on the entry of France in the second war of Italian independence.
        Dedication on cover: "à tous les orphéons de France."
        Purchased from Les Autographes on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 1998.
      - "La charité, pour l'amour de Dieu! quête pour les pauvres de Gallicia / Ch. Gounod", 1880 January 20; 1 ms. score ([5] p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 43)
        Score, holograph, dated at Paris.
        For contralto, chorus, violoncello, and piano.
        Holograph dedication: "à mon amie la Princesse Suzanna Czartoryska."
      - "Le monde est méchant, ma petite", undated; 1 ms. score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 52)
        Score, holograph, for a song for voice and piano, with text by Théophile Gautier.
        Piano part is incomplete.
        Purchased from Charavay on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 1998.
      - "Prologue: 1er tableau: La porte de l'enfer", undated; 2 ms. score fragments ([11] p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 56)
        Score fragments, holograph, from an unidentified work.
      - Sketches for unidentified string quartet, [1830s?]; [3] p. of ms. music; 26 x 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 44)
        Two sketches, in short and full score, holograph, including a minuet and trio.
        Paper is watermarked 1836.
      - "Sujet de fugue", undated; [1] p. of ms. music; 18 x 26 cm. (Box Folder 385)
        Subject and fragment of a fugue in four parts, holograph, signed at end.
        Ownership stamp on verso: Max Thorek, Chicago.
        Purchased from William Reese Co. on the Library Associates Fund, 2003.
  - Other Papers
    - "Histoire de la civilization en Angleterre par Henry Thomas Buckle, traduite ... par Charles Gounod", n.d.; 1 item (23 leaves); 22 cm. (Box Folder 259)
      Translation, holograph, of the first chapter of Buckle's History of Civilization in England (London: J. W. Parker and Son, 1857-1861).
    - "La devise râepublicaine et l'oraison dominicale", [not after 1893]; 1 item (16 p.); 11 cm. x 18 cm. (Box Folder 260)
      Autograph manuscript of a meditation on the Revolutionary motto "Liberté, Egalité, Fraternité" and its relationship to the Christian faith.
      Purchased from Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke, Jr. Fund, 1997.
- Grétry, André Ernest Modeste, 1741-1813
  - Correspondence
    - [Ljoyard?], Monsieur, an XII 27 pluvôise [i.e. 1804 Jan 17]; 1 item (2 p.); 19 cm., mounted on sheet, 39 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      Brief ALS, Paris, to [Ljoyard?], Paris, expressing gratitude.
      Mounted on a leaf with letter from D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit) Auber.
      Former group number: 30 GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE
      Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, 2000 May 26, lot 114) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Grove, George, Sir, 1820-1900
  - Correspondence
    - Fusco, Madame, 1875-77; 3 items. (Box Folder 261)
      Three ALS, London, to Fusco, Naples, regarding publication of lectures on Italian art and literature in MacMillan's Magazine, for which Grove worked as editor.
      Former group number: 31 GROVE, GEORGE
      Purchased from Maggs Brothers, Ltd., on the William Lyon Phelps Memorial Fund, 1959.
- Guiraud, Ernest, 1837-1892
  - Correspondence
    - Joncières, Victorin, 1879, n.d.; 3 items. (Box Folder 262)
      Three brief ALS, Paris, dated 1897 Nov 27; n.y. Feb 21, concerning a meeting of composers; and n.d., mentioning Léon Carvalho.
      Former group number: 32 GUIRAUD, ERNEST
- Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947
  - Correspondence
    - Bondeville, Emmanuel, 1939-44, n.d.; 17 items. (Box Folder 263)
      14 ALS and 3 autograph postcards signed, discussing vocal music, plans to edit composers' letters, style of composers, and other musical issues.
      Former group number: 33 HAHN, REYNALDO
      Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, London, 1997 Dec 5, lot 83) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Bondy, François, 1940 January 11-17; 2 items. (Box Folder 447)
      2 autograph letters, signed, referring to music of Richard Wagner.
      Purchased from Galerie Arts et Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
    - Boschot, Adolphe, 1913-45, n.d.; 13 items. (Box Folder 264)
      Twelve ALS, with three envelopes, and two postcards, holograph, signed, discussing musical matters.
    - Bourdillon de Gastinoy, Odette, [1919 July 8]; 1 item (4 p.). (Box Folder 446)
      Autograph letter, signed, with envelope, about friendship.
      Purchased from L'Autographe S. A. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Bresson, Sergent, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 15 cm. (Box Folder 265)
      ALS to Bresson, S/Intendance, conveying Lt. Luzarche's questions about paying his convoy.
    - Brisson, Pierre, 1920, [1939]; 2 items. (Box Folder 266)
      Two ALS to Pierre Brisson, about reviews.
    - Brisson, Pierre, undated; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 434)
      Autograph letter, signed, about Hahn's schedule of engagements, including opera conducting and radio appearances.
      Purchased from Lisa Cox on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 2002.
    - Dubois, Théodore, [1905 July?]; 1 item (4 p.). (Box Folder 445)
      Autograph letter, signed, responding to an accusation that Hahn had attempted to photograph an examination at the Paris Conservatoire.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot, Pierre Pruvost Paris sale, 2002 November 26, lot 137) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Escande, Maurice, 1943 June 10; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 435)
      Typed letter, signed, about an accusation made against Hahn by Vina Bovy, and responses from Jacques Rouché and Pierre Bessand-Massenet.
      Purchased from Galerie Arts et Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Garcet de Vauresmont, Madamoiselle, [1920], undated; 2 items. (Box Folder 450)
      2 autograph letters, signed, responding to an invitation, and about performances by Hahn and Garcet de Vauresmont's singing.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot sale, 2002 April 11-12, lot 358) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Halphen, Émile, Madame, [1935 May 22]; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 431)
      Autograph letter, signed, declining an invitation.
    - Lemaire, Madeleine-Jeanne Coll, [circa 1912?]; 2 items. (Box Folder 443)
      Autograph letter, signed, about Hahn's travel in Algeria, and mentioning Charles-Marie Widor; and an autgraph note, signed, to "cher ami," a pianist, expressing congratulations.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot, Pierre Pruvost Paris sale, 2002 November 26, lot 139) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Lugnier, Antonin, [1918 December 19]; 1 item (3 p.). (Box Folder 439)
      Autograph letter, signed, with envelope, declining to set a poem by Lugnier to music, and referring to Hahn's military service. Accompanied by brief notes about the letter, manuscript in an unidentified hand.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot sale, 2002 September 27, lot 10) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Mauvernay, Madame, 1911 Jan 11; 1 item (2 p.); 19 cm. (Box Folder 267)
      ALS, Paris, declining an invitation. Accompanied by a statement of authenticity, signed by D. Janvier, 1948 Jan 13.
    - Muhlfeld, Lucien, 1899 and undated; 14 items. (Box Folder 432)
      13 autograph letters, signed, and one dictated letter, to Muhlfeld or his wife. The letters respond to invitations and discuss Hahn's music and travels.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot sale, 2001 December 17, lot 65) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Ochse, Fernand, 1932-37, n.d.; 5 items. (Box Folder 268)
      Four ALS and one postcard, holograph, signed, regarding concerts and responding to Ochse.
    - Ochse, Madame, n.d.; 3 items. (Box Folder 269)
      Three ALS regarding lessons for Fernand.
    - Patti, Adelina, [1907 March]; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 436)
      Autograph letter, signed, referring to Patti's peformance in Gioacchino Rossini's Barbiere di Siviglia in a private theater of Jean de Reszke, and to Luigi Venzano's Ah! che assorta.
      Purchased from L'Autographe S. A. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Peter, René, [1906], [1938]; 5 items. (Box Folder 437)
      3 autograph letters, signed, with one envelope, concerning invitations, their friendship, and Hahn's travel to Egypt; with 2 photographs, 1938 February-March, of Hahn in rehearsal with unidentified singers, at the "Petit Théatre de l'Opera," and in Egypt.
      Dates from postmarks.
    - Reuillard, Gabriel, 1922-33, n.d.; 6 items. (Box Folder 270)
      Four brief ALS and two brief TL concerning an article written by Hahn and social engagements.
    - Rey, [C.?], [1909 July 26]; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 444)
      Autograph letter, signed, with address leaf, to "mon cher ami," about Jean de Reszke.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot, Pierre Pruvost Paris sale, 2002 November 26, lot 138) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Thibaud, Anna, [1928 November]; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 430)
      Autograph letter, signed, about Thibaud's singing.
    - Warnod, André, 1 item (2 p.); 27 cm. (Box Folder 272)
      ALS concerning music critics.
    - Warnod, André, 1935, n.d.; 2 items. (Box Folder 271)
      ALS, postmarked 1935 May 16; and ALS, n.d., referring to Pierre Brisson.
    - [Aubry, Raoul?], [1903 January 3?]; 1 item (3 p.). (Box Folder 448)
      Autograph letters, signed, to "cher ami," in response to a favorable article about Hahn's music, referring to influence on Hahn's music by Jules Massenet and Camille Saint-Saëns.
    - [Lebaudy, Pierre?], undated; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 449)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "mon cher ami," about a performance of Hahn's ballet Bal de Béatrice d'Este for "Madame Lebaudy's" soirée, and discussing fees paid by wealthy patrons.
    - Unidentified, [1901]; 1 item (2 p.); 10 x 14 cm. (Box Folder 273)
      ALS, Berneville, referring to Madame Patorni.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 274)
      ALS to "Chere Madame" regarding performances that he will give the following day.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 22 cm. (Box Folder 275)
      ALS to "Chère Madame" concerning a purchase of rice, and regarding a concert.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot sale, 1997 Nov 6-7, no. 233) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 28 x 8 cm. (Box Folder 276)
      Brief ALS to "Mon cher President et ami," concerning an adaptation of Franz Schubert's Die schoene Muellerin.
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 433)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "cher ami," responding to three unidentified questions. Hahn's responses concern moral progress and refer to slavery in America.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot sale, 2001 December 17, lot 64) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Unidentified, [1924], undated; 2 items. (Box Folder 438)
      2 autograph letters, signed, to "chére Madame," acknowledging a letter; and to "cher ami," about performance of Hahn's music.
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 440)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "cher Monsieur," about a portrait of Paul Verlaine by Eugène Carrière.
      Purchased from Demarest on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 item (3 p.). (Box Folder 441)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "Monsieur," responding to criticisms of Hahn's writings on music, and referring to Jean Cocteau.
    - Unidentified, [circa 1945?]; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 442)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "chère Madame," about memories of their friendship.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot, Pierre Pruvost Paris sale, 2002 November 26, lot 140) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 451)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "cher Monsieur," about a rehearsal.
  - Music
    - Au pays musulman
      Song, with text by Henri de Régnier.
      Composed 1906.
      - "Le pays mussulman", [circa 1906]; 1 ms. score ([15] leaves); 36 cm. (Box Volume 42)
        Score, holograph, signed at end, with printer's markings.
        Title on cover: Souvenir de Constantinople.
        Plate number in manuscript: H. & Cie 22990 (Heugel).
        Signed by printer on verso of last page, 1906 June 8.
        Purchased from Bernard Quaritch (Sotheby's sale, 2001 May 25, lot 101) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2001.
    - Bal de Béatrice d'Este; arr.
      Ballet suite.
      Composed 1909.
      - "Le bal de Béatrice d'Este: suite pour instruments à vent, deux harpes et un piano / Reynaldo Hahn", undated; 2 parts (33, 33 p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 63)
        Printed parts for a transcription for two pianos (Paris: Heugel, undated).
        Plate number: H. et Cie. 22,600. 22,601.
        Purchased from Pierre Berès (Artus Encheres & Brissounneau sale, Hotel Drouot, 2004 May 18-19, lot 108) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
    - Muses pleurant la mort de Ruskin
      For women's voices, 2 choruses (women's voices), and lyres.
      Published 1902.
      - "Les muses pleurant la mort de Ruskin / Reynaldo Hahn", c1925; 1 score (30 p.); 29 cm. (Box Folder 388)
        Printed score (Paris: Heugel, c1925), inscribed on cover to "Madame Duglé."
        Plate number: 28,892.
        Beginning of score annotated in an unidentified hand with names of singers.
    - Offrande
      Song, with text by Paul Verlaine.
      Composed 1891.
      - "Offrande / poésie de Paul Verlaine; musique de Reynaldo Hahn", undated; 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 61)
        Printed score (Paris: Quinzard, undated), inscribed on cover to "Madame Duglé," 1891 November.
        Plate number: A. Q. et Cie. 51.
        Performance annotations in an unidentified hand.
    - Plus beau présent
      Song, with text by Maurice Magre.
      Published 1917.
      - "Tu m'as donné un coussin de soie / poésie de Maurice Magre; musique de Reynaldo Hahn", 1916; 1 ms. score ([5] p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 58)
        Score, copyist's manuscript, with annotations by Hahn. Signed at end, Vraincourt, 1916.
        Stamp on cover: "Copie de musique, Leon Duclos."
        Purchased from Pierre Berès (Artus Encheres & Brissounneau sale, Hotel Drouot, 2004 May 18-19, lot 107) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
    - Si mes vers avaient des ailes
      Composed 1888.
      - "Si mes vers avaient des ailes! / poésie de Victor Hugo; musique de Reynaldo Hahn", undated; 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 62)
        Printed score (Paris: Heugel, undated).
        Caption title.
        Plate number: H. et Cie. 7474.
        Annotatation on cover: "H. Tauber."
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified fragment, undated; [1] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 60)
        Fragment of music for keyboard, holograph, inscribed to an unidentified recipient and signed with initials.
        Caption: "No. 12. Assez lent."
        Annotated: "Le motif se reproduit avec des variantes nombreuses."
        Purchased from Pierre Berès (Artus Encheres & Brissounneau sale, Hotel Drouot, 2004 May 18-19, lot 106) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
      - "Venite exultemus: extract du Ps. LXXXXIV / R. H.", 1923 September 6; 1 ms. score ([8] p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 59)
        Score, holograph. Dated at end, 1923 September 6, La Pérelle.
        On title page: "à M. Guy Gerrant pour chanter au lutrin."
        Purchased from Pierre Berès (Artus Encheres & Brissounneau sale, Hotel Drouot, 2004 May 18-19, lot 105) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
  - Other Papers
    - "Pour les lecteurs de "La semaine égyptienne", undated; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 429)
      Autograph manuscript, signed, about opera performances in Egypt.
      On verso: letterhead of the Continental-Savoy hotel, Cairo.
      Purchased from Les Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2000.
    - "Proust et Ruskin", 1945 Apr 21; 1 item (2 p.); 28 cm. (Box Folder 279)
      Article, typescript carbon.
      Accompanied by a clipping of a portait of John Ruskin by John Everett Millais from an unidentified publication.
      Gift, 1976.
    - La meche noire, n.d.; 1 item (ca. 125 p.); 26 cm. (Box Folder 277-278)
      Ten chapters of novel (fragment), holograph, corrected.
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Folder 264, 1941, 1945; 2 items. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 7)
- Halévy, F., 1799-1862
  - Correspondence
    - Deschamps, Emile, [18]56 Jan 4; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 280)
      ALS, Paris, to "Mon cher & illustre poete" requesting some poetry and discussing their next meeting.
      Former group number: 34 HALEVY, F.
    - Deschamps, Emile, 1856 May 9; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 281)
      ALS, Paris, to "Cher & aimable poete" regarding Halevy's trip to Paris.
    - Halevy, Ludovic, [18]58 Sep 21; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 282)
      One ALS to his nephew, mainly in verse, asking him why he has abandoned his relatives.
    - Moscheles, Ignaz, 1830 Nov 16; 1 item (2 p.); 20 cm., mounted on sheet, 39 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      ALS concerning a social engagement with Luigi Cherubini, and referring to a canon by Cherubini and a setting of Heinrich Heine written by Halévy in Moscheles's album.
      Mounted on a leaf with letter from Charles Gounod.
    - Rodrigues, Edouard, 1837 Apr 8; 1 item (1 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 283)
      ALS sending an invitation.
      Purchased from Clive Farahar & Sophie Dupre on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1997.
    - Scribe, Eugene, n.d.; 2 items. (Box Folder 284)
      Two ALS, one regarding Mlle. Grevedon's performance in Les Huguenots.
      Purchased from Autographes on the George Henry Nettleton Fund.
    - Unidentified, 1851, n.d.; 3 items. (Box Folder 285)
      ALS to "Edouard" and signed "your old friend and youngest cousin"; ALS to "Mon cher de France"; and ALS to "Mon cher poete."
  - Music
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified fragment, 1854 March 1; 1 ms. score fragment ([1] p.); 25 x 33 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 64)
        Score fragment, holograph, inscribed to Alfred Beauchesne.
        Annotation: "Fragment d'un morceau intitulé Chant breton, extrait des Souvenirs poëtique de Mr. Alcide Beauchêne [i.e. Beauchesne]...."
        Accompanied by two engraved portraits and reproductions of two photographs of Halévy.
        Purchased from Moirandat Company AG (Stargardt Berlin sale, 2004 March 23-24, lot 827) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
- Halévy, Ludovic, 1834-1908
  - Correspondence
    - Aubernon de Nerville, Madame, n.y. Dec [5?]; 1 item (1 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 286)
      ALS expressing gratitude.
      Former group number: 35 HALEVY, LUDOVIC
      Purchased from Degrange with funds given by the Yale Library Associates, 1953 Oct 18.
    - Claretie, Jules, [1885]; 1 item (4 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 287)
      ALS discussing his views on hypnotism and Jules Bernard Luys and briefly referring to Alexandre Dumas.
    - Du Mesnil, Armand, 1857-91, n.d.; 15 items. (Box Folder 288)
      Fifteen ALS to Armand Du Mesnil, and possibly others, including a letter concerning Eugene Fromentin, with an ALS to Fromentin from Du Mesnil on verso; letters discussing Halevy's L'abbe Constantin, Du Mesnil's Propos interrompus, and other literary matters; and brief letters concerning social engagements.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 17 cm. (Box Folder 289)
      Brief ALS in appreciation for an expression of sympathy.
      Purchased from La Licorne on the Edward Wells Southworth Fund, 1931 Jul 28.
- Harsányi, Tibor, 1898-1954
  - Music
    - Invités. Vocal score
      Opera, with text by Jean-Victor Pellerin, from his play Intimité.
      - "Les invités: opera en 15 minutes / livret de Jean-Victor Pellerin, tiré de sa piece Intimité; musique de Tibor Harsányi", 1927 December-1928 January; 1 ms. vocal score (38 p.); 36 cm. (Box Volume 43)
        Holograph vocal score, with corrections and performance markings. Dated at end, 1927 December-1928 January, Paris.
- Hérold, Ferdinand, 1791-1833
  - Music
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified fragment from an opera chorus, undated; 1 ms. score fragment ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 65)
        Score fragment, holograph, with corrections.
        Text begins: "Le calme succède à l'orage...."
        Accompanied by a copyist's manuscript of the same music.
- Hervé, 1825-1892
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, 1874 Jul 14; 1 item (2 p.); 17 cm., mounted on sheet, 39 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      ALS, [London?], to "Chère Madame," about a song Hervé intends to compose for her.
      Mounted on a leaf with letter from Félicien David.
      Former group number: 36 HERVE
- Hofmann, Josef, 1876-1957
  - Other Papers
    - Signature, 1923 Jan 23; 1 item (1 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 290)
      Quotation from an unidentified work, inscribed to S. C. S. Watkins and signed by Hofmann.
      Former group number: 36 HOFMANN, JOSEF
- Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955
  - Correspondence
    - Pélissier, Paul, 1925-1929, undated; 3 items. (Box Folder 422)
      Autograph note, signed, postmarked 1925 November 26, declining an invitation, on a postcard with image of an unidentified singer as Holopherne in Aleksandr Nikolaevich Serov's opera Judith.
      Accompanied by a postcard with reproduction of a photograph of Honegger, inscribed to an unidentified recipient, 1929; and an autograph music quotation, signed, from an unidentified string quartet.
      Purchased from Bernard Quaritch (Sotheby's sale, 2001 December 7, lot 69) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
  - Music
    - Jeanne d'Arc au bûcher. Vocal score
      Oratorio, with text by Paul Claudel.
      Composed 1935; prologue added 1944.